<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Senior software engineer on Antoni Karasavov</title>
    <link>/</link>
    <description>Recent content in Senior software engineer on Antoni Karasavov</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en-gb</language>
    <lastBuildDate>Fri, 26 Jun 2020 12:40:19 +0100</lastBuildDate>
    
	<atom:link href="/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    
    
    <item>
      <title>Announcing xpoz: An API and a web viewer for Apple&#39;s Photos.app</title>
      <link>/posts/xpoz-an-api-for-apple-photos-app/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 01 Jan 2021 01:19:00 +0100</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/posts/xpoz-an-api-for-apple-photos-app/</guid>
      <description>Let&amp;rsquo;s kick off the new year with something positive! I&amp;rsquo;m happy to announce
 xpoz: An API and a web viewer for your Apple Photos.app albums.
 This is the result of some hacking around with Photos.app I did earlier in 2020. After figuring out how things worked more or less, I decided to have a go at writing an API that would expose all the stored metadata and possibly serve the images as well.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Work</title>
      <link>/work/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 26 Jun 2020 16:56:41 +0100</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/work/</guid>
      <description>Metropolitan Thames Valley MTVH needed help moving their stack of Rails apps from being built by an agency to developing them in-house.
My role required transferring knowledge to the in-house dev team (capability building I think is the buzz word). I mentored and provided guidance to junior engineers, schooling them in various programming topics - both practical and theoretical, while taking part in regular sprint work.
I&amp;rsquo;ve extended my contract to oversee the completion of the transition, finish some important improvements on their residents&amp;rsquo; portal, and onboard my worthy two senior successors who I also helped in hiring.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Ghetto Brightness Control</title>
      <link>/posts/ghetto-brightness-control/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 20 May 2020 17:23:17 +0100</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/posts/ghetto-brightness-control/</guid>
      <description>This is the second post in the series where I&amp;rsquo;m trying to switch away from the mac for a while.
One of the things I miss is the ability to adjust brightness of my monitor with the multimedia keyboard keys. When at home, my mac is usually hooked up to a 22&amp;rdquo; LG UltraFine, which controls its brightness automatically based on the ambient light sensor on the laptop, or I could adjust it by holding ctrl and using the brigthness keys on my MX Keys keyboard.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Development setup on Linux</title>
      <link>/posts/linux-dev-setup/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 19 Apr 2020 00:25:04 +0100</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/posts/linux-dev-setup/</guid>
      <description>I recently bought a new computer. I couldn&amp;rsquo;t have timed it better even if I wanted to. My everyday laptop has started exhibiting the notorious keyboard problem and brought my productivity down to that of a goldfish. Off to the Apple Store to get it sorted (more on that in a future post) and on with setting up a Linux on my new workstation.
Last time I tried this exercise was about a decade ago, so stepping into unfamiliar territory I went for something popular - Pop OS!</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Got a new mini PC. What should I do with it?</title>
      <link>/posts/asrock-a300/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 08 Apr 2020 23:44:15 +0100</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/posts/asrock-a300/</guid>
      <description>Nostalgia hit me the other day while watching a random YouTube video of a guy building a PC. This and the fact that I&amp;rsquo;ve been toying around with the idea of getting a small computer for my desk at home led me to make an impulsive purchase of this little ASRock A300.
It&amp;rsquo;s absolutely brilliant with size comparable to the original mac mini, maybe even smaller. Not entirely sure of the exact purpose of this build, I picked up the Ryzen 3200G, 16G of memory, the cheapest 250GB solid state drive I could find from Scan, a wifi card, and a Noctua slim fan.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>The Apple Photos library</title>
      <link>/posts/apple-photos/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 06 Jan 2020 01:19:00 +0100</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/posts/apple-photos/</guid>
      <description>UPDATE (01-01-2021): The findings below have led to the announcement of an app which exposes an API and a web viewer for the albums in your Photos.app
 All the information here was compiled by me looking at the library folder, examining the sqlite databases, monitoring changes in files, hexdumping, etc. while playing around with my personal photos collection.
Do what you want with this, but keep in mind it is unofficial and solely based on my personal observations, therefore it is incomplete and some parts could be plain wrong.</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>