<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Linux as an alternative to mac for work on Antoni Karasavov</title>
    <link>/series/linux-as-an-alternative-to-mac-for-work/</link>
    <description>Recent content in Linux as an alternative to mac for work on Antoni Karasavov</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en-gb</language>
    <lastBuildDate>Wed, 20 May 2020 17:23:17 +0100</lastBuildDate>
    
	<atom:link href="/series/linux-as-an-alternative-to-mac-for-work/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    
    
    <item>
      <title>Ghetto Brightness Control</title>
      <link>/posts/ghetto-brightness-control/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 20 May 2020 17:23:17 +0100</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/posts/ghetto-brightness-control/</guid>
      <description>This is the second post in the series where I&amp;rsquo;m trying to switch away from the mac for a while.
One of the things I miss is the ability to adjust brightness of my monitor with the multimedia keyboard keys. When at home, my mac is usually hooked up to a 22&amp;rdquo; LG UltraFine, which controls its brightness automatically based on the ambient light sensor on the laptop, or I could adjust it by holding ctrl and using the brigthness keys on my MX Keys keyboard.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Development setup on Linux</title>
      <link>/posts/linux-dev-setup/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 19 Apr 2020 00:25:04 +0100</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/posts/linux-dev-setup/</guid>
      <description>I recently bought a new computer. I couldn&amp;rsquo;t have timed it better even if I wanted to. My everyday laptop has started exhibiting the notorious keyboard problem and brought my productivity down to that of a goldfish. Off to the Apple Store to get it sorted (more on that in a future post) and on with setting up a Linux on my new workstation.
Last time I tried this exercise was about a decade ago, so stepping into unfamiliar territory I went for something popular - Pop OS!</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>